[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
We talked about accuracy and errors that a classifier might make.
前面我们讨论了分类器的准确率和误差率
But there are different kinds of errors.
但误差也有若干种不同的类型
So this kind of errors are called types of mistakes.
这类误差被称为"错误"
It's important to look at the types of mistakes a classifier might make.
发现分类器可能会犯的错误 是一件非常需要重视的事
And one way to do that is through what's called a confusion matrix.
我们用"混淆矩阵"来研究这些错误
So, let's take that in a little bit.
让我们来看看混淆矩阵吧
So we're talking about the relationship between the true label and
我们一直在讨论 真标签 和 分类器预测结果之间的关系
whatever classifier predicts, so the predicted label.
分类器预测结果 也叫做 预测标签
So let's say that if the true label is positive, and we predict a positive value
假如说 真标签是正面情绪 我们也预测那个句子情绪为正
for that sentence, we call that a true positive because we got it right.
这种情况下我们称之为 真正类 因为我们预测对了
Similarly if the true label is negative and
类似的是 如果真标签为负面情绪
we predict that negative we call that a true negative.
我们也预测了负面情绪 这种情况我们称之为 真负类
That's good cuz we got that right.
这种情况也很好 因为我们又预测对了
Now, there is two kinds of mistakes that I can make.
我们可能犯两种错误
So, for example, if the true label's positive, but
比如说 如果真标签为正面情绪
we predicted as negative, we call that a false negative.
但我们预测为负 这就被称为 假负面
We said it was negative, but that was false cuz it's positive.
我们以为它是负面 但这是假的 因为它是正面的
Similarly, if the true label is negative when we predicted as positive,
类似地 如果真标签为负面 但我们预测的为正面
we call that a false positive.
我们就称之为 假正类
It was negative, but we predicted it as positive.
因为它是负面 却被我们预测为正面
And false positives and false negatives can have different impacts
假正面 和 假负面 对你的分类器的实际影响
on what can happen in practice with your classifier.
可能是不一样的
So let's look at a couple practical examples of that.
让我们来看几个实际中的例子
So let's look at two applications, and
我们来看看两个应用
what the cost has of false positives versus false negatives.
看看假正类和假负类的不同代价
So, if you consider spam filtering, a false negative is
比如说 在思考垃圾邮件的过滤器的时候
an email that was spam but went into my folder it thought it was not spam.
在这里假负类是指这封信其实是个垃圾邮件 但被我们归类进了邮件列表
So that's just annoying I got another spam email in my inbox.
那么我的收件箱里就又多了一封垃圾邮件 这有点烦人
Maybe it's bad but not super bad.
有点令人不爽 但还不算太糟
However, if you look at a false positive
但是 再来看看假正类
that's an email that was not spam that got labeled as spam, went to my spam filter.
那是指一封正常邮件被标记成了垃圾邮件 扔进了垃圾邮件箱
I never saw it, I lost that email forever.
我压根看都没看到它 就永远失去了它
That has a higher cost.
这个错误代价就高了
Now we can also look at medical diagnosis or
我们再看看另一个例子
other applications as a second application.
医学诊断的应用
So what's a false negative in medical diagnosis?
医学诊断中的假负类是什么呢?
False negative is, there's a disease that I have but
那是指我明明有某种病 但是没诊断出来
it didn't get detected, so the classifier said it was negative.
所以分类器说结果为阴性
They don't have the disease.
我没病
So in this case, the disease goes untreated,
这种情况下 我也就没去治
which can be a really bad thing.
这可是非常糟糕的情况
But the false positives can also be a bad thing.
但是假正类也可能很糟糕
That is, I classify as having the disease when I never had the disease.
那就是 我被诊断患有某种疾病 但其实我根本就没有
In this case I get treated potentially with a really bad drug or
我可能需要服用一些虎狼之药
false side effect for diseases that I never had.
忍受各种副作用 然而我压根没病
So it's a little bit unclear what's worse, having a false positive or
所以说医疗诊断中 假正类和假负类
a false negative.
到底哪个更糟 真的不一定说得清楚
In medialc complications it really depends on the cost of the treatment and
在医学处理中 这很依赖于治疗成本
how many side effects it had versus how bad the disease can be.
副作用多少 和 这病到底会有多糟
Now this relationship between the true label and the predicted label,
这里真标签和预测标签 以及假正类 假负类之间的关系
false positive, false negatives, is called the Confusion Matrix.
就被称做混淆矩阵
This matrix we just do.
就是我们刚刚讨论的内容
So for example, let's say that we have a setting with a 100 test examples.
我们再举个有具体数据的例子 假设我们有100个测试样本
And we have of those, 60 positive and 40 are negative.
其中60个的真标签为正面 40个为负面
So there's a little bit of class imbalance but not too much.
有一点点类别不平衡但是差的不很多
So of those 60 true positives, if I say I got 50 of them correct,
在这60个真标签为正面的样本中 我们预测对了50个
well of the 42 negatives
而在这40个真标签为负面的样本中
I got 35 of them correct.
我们预测对了35个
Let's see what we've learned.
现在来看看我们都知道了些什么
So out of the 100 examples I got 85 correct.
所以说在这100个样本中 我预测对了85个
So we can talk about our accuracy.
这是我的正确率
Accuracy is 85 correct over 100, which is 0.85.
正确率是85/100  也就是0.85
And we can also discuss the true positives and the true negatives.
再让我们来看看真正类和真负类
Sorry, the false positives and the false negatives, so of the positives,
噢不 看看假正类和假负类
I got labeled as negative, that's a false negative.
在真标签为正面的样本中 如果我预测为正面 那就是假负类
And that was ten, I had ten false negatives and on the other hand,
这种情况有10次 这就是我的假负面数值
of the true negatives we get five false positive.
另一方面 在真标签为负面的样本中 我预测了5个为正面 这就是假正类数值
So in this example, we got 85% accuracy.
所以这个例子中 我的准确率是85%
We got a higher false negative rate, than we had a false positive rate.
我的假负类率 高于假正类率
Now those words, false positive,
当然 假正面 假负面  这些词
false negative, apply only for minor classification for two classes.
只适用于只有两个类别的分类问题
But the ideal confusion matrix works well even when you have more classes.
但理想情况下的混淆矩阵 也能处理我们有多种类别的情况
So let's talk about a simple example of that.
我们来看个简单例子
So let's say that I have 100 test examples and this is for
关于医疗诊断的例子 假如说我们有100个测试样本
medical diagnosis, so there's 3 classes, healthy, cold or flu.
有3种类别 健康 普通感冒 流感
And of the 100 test subjects we had 70 with that were healthy,
在100个测试样本中  70个人的真实状态是健康的
20 that had cold, and 10 that had the flu.
20个人有普通感冒 10个人是流感
And let's suppose that we got 60 correct for
假设我们预测对了 60个健康的人
healthy, we got 12 correct for cold,
12个普通感冒的人
and we got 60, 12, 8 correct for flu.
和8个流感的人
So, the total, our accuracy, here,
所以总的来说 我们的准确预测数是80
was 80, which is 60 plus 12 plus 8 divided by 100.
就是 60+12+8 准确率是80/100
So that 0.8, 80% accuracy.
也就是0.8  或说80%
But we can talk about the false predictions.
但我们也可以讨论错误的预测
So from healthy there were ten mistakes.
对健康人数来说 我们预测错了10个
And we can say it's more common to confuse healthy with having a cold
我们可以说 我们更容易把健康的人 和得普通感冒的人搞混
than it is with having the flu, because the flu is a more complex disease so
而更不容易把健康的人和得流感的人搞混 因为流感是一种更加复杂的疾病
we might have those ten mistakes.
所以在我们犯的这10个错误中
Eight were confused with code and two were confused with flu.
有8个健康的人被诊断成了普通感冒 2个被诊断成了流感
Cold can go both ways.
普通感冒既能和健康互相混淆 也能和流感混淆
So we made eight mistakes.
我们诊断错了8个得普通感冒的人
Maybe you can say half of them got confused with healthy and
其中一半被我们当成了健康人
half of them got diagnosis something stronger the flu.
另一半被我们诊断为患了流感
Well of the two mistakes for the flu, then maybe we say that we
对于那两个得了流感被诊断错的人
made no mistakes often, nobody that came in for flu was thought oh you're healthy.
我们可以假设一般情况下我们不会 把得了流感的人诊断成健康的人
But two of those ten were thought to have just a cold and not the flu.
但这两人被诊断成了普通感冒 而不是流感
So this is an example of a confusion matrix, we can really
这就是一个超过两种分类结果的混淆矩阵的例子
understand the types of mistakes we made and we can interpret those.
我们可以从中了解我们犯的各种错误 以及它们代表的意义到底是什么
And this is a really important thing to do in classification
这是分类问题中一个非常重要的部分 翻译：Jiajuan Liu ｜审阅：PhoenixLIU Coursera Global Translator Community